paymate.com 2012-05-03

# Security & Privacy | Paymate - Online payment service - sell online, buy online

Home > Security & Privacy

To help clients better understand the personal information we gather and the practices we employ, Paymate has developed a Privacy Policy that covers the following areas:

  * Information collected
  * Use and disclosure of information
  * Accessing and updating information about you
  * Security
  * Acceptance of and changes to this Privacy Policy
  * Contact details

This Privacy Policy applies to your use of the website operated under the domain name www.paymate.com, www2.paymate.com and www.haiwaibao.com (the "Paymate Website") and the services provided by Paymate Pty Ltd ABN 91 093 528 002.

In addition to this Privacy Policy, there may also be specific and additional privacy provisions that apply to particular Paymate services. Because those specific and additional provisions also relate to your privacy protection, you should review them carefully. To the extent of any inconsistency between the provisions of this Privacy Policy and those other specific and additional provisions, the specific and additional provisions will take priority.

Where this Privacy Policy refers to your "personal information", it means information about you (as an individual) from which your identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained. Your name and e-mail address are examples of personal information.

* * *

## Information collected

You can visit the Paymate Website and find out about our products and services without giving us any information about yourself. We may record certain non-personal information, such as your server address, domain name, the date and time of your visit and any pages viewed. That information will only be used for statistical and website administration purposes. To maintain visitor anonymity, we will not associate that information with records containing personal information unless you have consented for us to do so. 

When you register to use Paymate, we require your name, phone number, e-mail address, mailing address, bank account and/or credit card number, and credit card expiration date (if applicable). We will also record any changes you make to this information in the Change Profile section of the Paymate Website. We require this information in order to verify your identity and bank/credit card account authority, to contact you and to provide our services to you. Upon registration, we will provide you with a usercode and password to use Paymate.

If someone else wishes to use Paymate to pay you or receive money from you, we will collect any personal information that they provide about you that is necessary for us to contact you and to perform our services. We will not make any other use of that information if you are not registered with Paymate.

The Paymate Website may contain links to web sites operated by third parties and other websites may contain links to the Paymate Website ("Linked Websites"). If the operators of those Linked Websites collect information about you, we may have access to that information as part of our arrangements with those third parties. Linked Websites should contain their own privacy statements and the operators of Linked Websites are responsible for informing you about their own privacy practices.

When you buy or sell an item using Paymate, we will ask for confirmation of some of the details you have provided on registration, as well as information about the transaction, including the amount and relevant credit card or bank account information.

We may also collect personal information from you if you knowingly provide it to us, for example by sending us an e-mail or providing feedback.

* * *

## Use and disclosure of information

We will not use or disclose (share, sell or divulge) any of your personal information to third parties unless we have informed you, have been authorised by you, or are required or authorised to do so by law.

In order to provide our services or to assess your application, we may need to provide personal information to third parties and they may need to provide personal information about you to us. Purposes for which we may exchange personal information with third parties include to verify your identity or bankruptcy status, to process a transaction, to conduct a commercial credit check, to check for court judgments against you, and to confirm receipt of payment

We may also use your personal information:

  * for purposes related to our research, planning, product development, security, testing and risk management;
  * for purposes connected with the operation, administration, development or enhancement of the our services and the paymate Website; and
  * where we suspect that fraud or unlawful activity has been, is being or may be engaged in.

We may provide personal information about you to our service providers who assist us in providing our services and the Paymate Website. We will only disclose your personal information to those third party service providers on a confidential basis so that the service provider can effectively provide those services.

In particular, when processing credit card transactions, we will utilise systems that assist in minimising the risk of credit card fraud. Personal information that we collect about you, including your credit card details, demographic information, such as your address and date of birth, and information about the purchases you have conducted through this website, is required to provide a basis for credit card fraud risk analysis.

If you order a shipment through the Paymate Shipping Service, we will provide your personal information by email or other means to the organisation (e.g. DHL) providing the shipping service (as noted in the relevant section of the Paymate Website). That organisation - which may handle your personal information outside Australia - is responsible for its own privacy practices and you should inform yourself of that organisation's applicable privacy policies.

If you consent to this Privacy Policy, we will transfer the personal information that you have provided to us to third parties in countries outside Australia for the purposes of processing that information to minimise the risk of credit card fraud. The personal information, which is transferred for that purpose, will be stored in that third party's database for use in credit card fraud risk analysis.

If you do not provide us with:

  * your personal information, and;
  * your consent to this Privacy Policy;

then we will not be able to process your registration and / or credit card transactions.

When you participate in a Paymate transaction, information about you and the transaction will be available to the other party to the transaction. This information will include your name, e-mail address, business name and Australian Business Number if a business, telephone number, mailing address, shipping address, the date and amount of the transaction, however your credit card number and bank account number will not be shown to the other party. If you are a seller using the Paymate TrustMark, this information may be available to potential buyers, as well as the date from which you have been continually registered with Paymate and the number of payments you have received via Paymate since that date. You and other users must maintain the confidentiality of each other's personal information. Please note that other users may be located in a different country to you.

Although such situations are rare, you should be aware that we may disclose your personal information to third parties in any of the following circumstances:

  * where an investigation of fraud or unlawful activity has been or is being conducted by us and the information is disclosed to relevant persons or authorities; or
  * where the disclosure is required or authorised by law; or
  * where we believe that the disclosure is reasonably necessary to assist a law enforcement agency or an agency responsible for national security in the performance of its functions; or
  * for the preparation for or the conduct of legal proceedings or for the implementation of the orders of a court or tribunal.

In the event that a third party acquires the business assets of Paymate Pty Ltd, that third party may wish to acquire customer information. If this happens, we will take reasonable steps to notify you of any personal information which we propose to transfer and to provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of having your personal information transferred.

We use and disclose aggregated non-personally identifying information as part of our process of constantly improving our services.

* * *

## Credit Information

If you consent to this Privacy Policy, you agree that Paymate may give information about you to a credit reporting agency to obtain a consumer/commercial report about you and/or allow a credit reporting agency to create or maintain a credit information file containing information about you, listing defaults (minimum AU$100 and 60 days overdue) and exchange information with other credit providers under Sections 18(E)(1) and 18(K) of the Privacy Act 1988.

* * *

## Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies (such as Google AdWords) to serve ads on our web site and other web sites. These companies may use cookies to collect information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other web sites. They use this information to measure advertising effectiveness and to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. We may also email you with information about our new services and service features from time to time, but will always offer you the ability to 'opt out' of future mailings by clicking on an 'unsubscribe' link.  We may use third party service providers (such as WebCentral Promotions Manager) to distribute such email communications.

* * *

## Accessing and updating information about you

You can access and update your registration information the Change Profile section of the Paymate Website at any time once you have provided your usercode and password. You can also view your recent transactions there. If you need to access or correct any other personal information we hold about you and are unable to do so in the Change Profile section, please contact us using the “Contact Details” set out below. An access fee may be charged. In certain circumstances, we may not be required by law to allow you to access or correct your personal information. If that is the case, we will give you our reasons for that decision.

* * *

## Security

Paymate uses several mechanisms to protect the security and integrity of your personal information

  * All your transactions with Paymate are conducted in 'secure sessions' using the financial industry's Secure Socket Layer (SSL) standards with 128-bit encryption. You should check that your browser is compatible with SSL encryption. This is often indicated by a 'closed lock' icon at the bottom of your screen.
  * Your username and password are essential for you to access your account details or to conduct a payment transaction. For your own protection, Paymate requires you to keep these confidential and encourage you to change your password regularly. **Please ensure you never provide your Username and/or password to anyone in response to email requests. You will never be asked by Paymate to disclose such information legitimately.**
  * Paymate transfers financial data securely into the Australian payments clearing system via dedicated telecommunications lines and proprietary banking software to ensure the integrity of our direct debit and credit payments. We process our credit card payments similarly.
  * Paymate employs qualified, independent auditors to review our security standards and practices on a regular basis to ensure that our software, operational practices and management controls meet the stringent standards of the Australian financial industry.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed as completely secure. So while we strive to protect such information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once your personal information comes into our possession, we will take reasonable steps to protect that information from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

* * *

## Acceptance of and changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When a variation occurs, we will take reasonable steps to notify you by e-mail at the e-mail address you provide to us on registration, or we will refer you to the variation at the time you next use Paymate or the Paymate Website, or we will publish the Privacy Policy as so varied on the Paymate Website. You accept that by doing this, we have provided you with sufficient notice of variation. Continued use of Paymate and the Paymate Website by you is acceptance of the changed Privacy Policy and any information collected following will be subject to that changed Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is governed by the law of New South Wales, Australia and you and Paymate irrevocably submit to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of New South Wales, Australia.

* * *

## Contact details

If you have any questions or feedback about privacy or security please contact us at   clientservices@paymate.com or

Paymate

2105, Woodside Road, Woodside CA 94062 USA  
Telephone +1 866-376-7028  Fax: +1 650-366-6283.

or

Suite 2505, 31 Market Street Sydney NSW 2000 Australia  
Telephone +612 9283 6977 Fax: +612 9283 6944.
